Contact

roopa_mcnealis@alumni.gsb.s tanford.edu

www.linkedin.com/in/ roopamcnealis (LinkedIn) www.third-eye-consulting.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Strategy
Entrepreneurship
Business Strategy

Languages

Hindi (Limited Working)

Marathi (Native or Bilingual)

English (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Certified Materials & Resource Professional (CMRP)

Roopa McNealis

Administrative Director at Stanford Health Care, Supply Chain Systems and Analytics

Palo Alto

Summary

Roopa discovers value at the intersection of data and people.

An experienced strategy and operations executive, her professional experience extends from start-up to larger healthcare/technology/ consulting company roles and includes having worked in Europe, India and Silicon Valley.

Markets:

Healthcare providers, tech and biotech, Internet and online services, online coaching and learning platforms

Specialties:

Growth strategy, new market assessment, market segmentation, product and business planning, business strategy, reporting and analytics, project management, operations and process implementation

Experience

Stanford Health Care 4 years 9 months

Administrative Director, Supply Chain Systems and Analytics January 2020 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Palo Alto

Oversee the Master Data Management and Demand Planning functions within Supply Chain, responsible for developing and implementing leading supply chain technologies, systems and analytics in support of building a best-in-class supply chain organization for Stanford Medicine's network of hospitals and clinics.

Director, Clinical and Business Analytics (CBA) Strategic Projects July 2016 - January 2020 (3 years 7 months)

Palo Alto, CA

Lead value analytics programs to support hospital operational efficiency and improvement goals. Partner with senior business and operations executives across the organization on enterprise analytics and dashboards, improvement initiatives, data governance, and the selection and management of external analytics vendors.

Globiana Inc.
Chief Operating Officer
July 2014 - June 2016 (2 years)
Silicon Valley, CA

Responsible for aligning the technology, product planning, marketing, content and customer facing teams to meet the strategic goals of the company.

Globiana supports mobile employees through a coaching and digital learning platform that reduces move-related stress, delivers a better relocation experience, and teaches global dexterity skills.

Exponential Talent LLC

Leader, Data Analytics and Transformation Management April 2014 - December 2015 (1 year 9 months)

Provide consulting services to helps clients innovate, change and grow to tap the full power of today's diverse workforce. Develop and implement metrics and accountability frameworks to drive talent strategies and innovations that raise employee satisfaction and business performance. Projects include gender and diversity strategy, organization development, talent management and change/transformation.

MoveCircles
Founder
2014 - 2015 (1 year)
Palo Alto, CA

Create and launch suite of online MoveCircles programs to transform the experience of moving to a new place. Members sign up for location and interest-specific circles to connect with groups of peers and share real-time learnings, experience-based advice, tips and tools.

Third Eye Consulting Marketing and Strategy Consultant 2001 - July 2014 (13 years) Tackle strategic, marketing, business development and project management challenges using a methodology based on discovery, issue framing, idea generation, data gathering and analysis, and common sense. Clients include high-tech, life sciences, and non-profit companies.

Flocktree Ltd.
Co-Founder
2011 - 2013 (2 years)
Palo Alto, CA

Co-founded Flocktree, a global online community of families living abroad. Hands-on with all parts of the business including strategy, product management, website development, marketing, operations and business development.

Gilead Sciences Consultant, Project Management & Corporate Strategy October 2004 - October 2006 (2 years 1 month)

areas, marketing and project management.

Analyzed R&D project spend and made recommendations to support senior management. Developed practical and rigorous R&D planning and portfolio management models. Created and instituted new knowledge management frameworks to improve alignment between the finance function, R&D functional

Terraspring Strategic Advisor 1999 - 2000 (1 year) Fremont, CA

Foster City, CA

Contributed in a multi-disciplinary role to support broad range of marketing and strategic needs as an early member of the team creating a cloud computing infrastructure and service. Company acquired by Sun Microsystems.

Arthur D. Little Manager 1996 - 1999 (3 years) Palo Alto, CA

Served global technology clients with strategic market management and international business strategy at the corporate, business unit and product/ service levels.

Ascom Timeplex Software Engineer 1992 - 1994 (2 years)

Designed and developed graphical applications to manage LAN and WAN networks. Assessed team requirements and helped formulate resource and budget allocations.

Ascom AG Software Engineer 1990 - 1992 (2 years)

Education

Stanford University Graduate School of Business MBA, Business

University of Maryland College Park BS, cum laude, Computer Science

Modern School